

🛘 (+33) 625370093 | 🗖 arthur.ouaknine@telecom-paris.fr | 🏕 arthurouaknine.github.io/ | 🛅 arthur-ouaknine | 💆 @ArthurOuaknine

# Summary\_

l'm a PhD student at Telecom Paris (Image, Data and Signal department) and Valeo.ai international research center in artificial intelligence applied to autonomous driving. The aim of my work is to use and adapt deep neural network architectures for scene understanding using automotive radar data and multi-sensor fusion. This work consists in using Range-Angle-Doppler representation of radar data and natural images for scene understanding. Our first contribution is an open source dataset of raw radar data using a semi-automatic algorithm to generate annotations.

## Education

**Telecom Paris** Palaiseau, France

Ph.D. STUDENT IN DEEP LEARNING

2019 - Now

- Under the supervision of P. Pérez (valeo.ai), F. Tupin (Telecom Paris) and A. Newson (Telecom Paris).
- Subject: "Scene understanding using deep learning algorithms applied to radar data for autonomous driving".
- · Keywords: deep learning algorithms, signal processing, computer vision, semi-automatic annotations, Range-Angle-Doppler representation.

**Telecom Paris** Palaiseau, France

POST M.Sc. MACHINE LEARNING (WITH HIGHEST HONORS)

2017-2018

- Keywords: Machine Learning, Big Data and Distributed Systems (Spark, Hadoop).
- Data Science Project: "Active learning for facial keypoint detection using deep learning".

## **Paris Pantheon-Sorbonne University**

Paris, France

M.Sc. STATISTICAL MODELLING (WITH HONORS)

2014 - 2016

## **Paris Diderot University**

Paris, France

**B.S. APPLIED MATHEMATICS** 

2011 - 2014

# **Experience**

Valeo.ai Paris, France

Ph.D. STUDENT IN DEEP LEARNING

2019 - Now

- Creation of a open source radar and camera dataset for scene understanding application. Annotations are generated on radar representations using a semi-supervised algorithm based on natural images. Current and futur work: deep learning architectures for scene understanding using radar data and sensor fusion.
- · Assistant Professor in computer vision and machine learning.
- Paper submission at ICPR 2020.
- Co-organizer of the Deep Learning Working Group of the IMAGES team at Telecom Paris.

Valeo.ai Paris, France

RESEARCH ENGINEER • Discussions between Valeo and Telecom team members about Radar theory and data.

- Creation of a radar simulator for data generation.
- Classification of the simulated data using deep learning.

**Faircast** Paris, France

RESEARCH ENGINEER (FREELANCE)

Jun 2018

Sep 2018 - Dec 2018

 3D point cloud segmentation using Superpoint Graph (L. Landrieu and M. Simonovsky, CVPR 2018) on LiDAR data for object removal in parisian apartment.

Zyl Saint-Maur-des-Fossés, France

COMPUTER VISION ENGINEER

DATA SCIENCE PROJECT

Oct 2016 - Jun 2017

- · Application of deep learning methods for computer vision (object detection) embedded on smartphone (compression).
- Deep Learning modelling for Visual Sentiment Analysis (D. Borth et al., ACM 2013) and transfer learning.
- · State-of-the-Art review of deep learning applied to image classification, object detection and model compression.

Idemia Paris, France

· Facial keypoint detection using deep neural networks with a few number of labelled data.

Oct 2016 - Jun 2017

- · Active learning process with uncertainty quantification for training optimization using Monte Carlo Dropout (Y. Gal and Z. Ghahramani, ICML 2016)

MAY 8, 2020 ARTHUR QUAKNINE · RÉSUMÉ Rexel Paris, France

DATA SCIENTIST Apr 2016 - Sep 2016

- Machine learning modelling for client targeting (churn probability prediction, elasticity estimation, commercial visit optimisation)
- Text mining analysis to target clients discontent.
- Machine learning for attrition prediction: churn probability prediction covering a large part of sale revenues, churn cause analysis.

Enedis Paris, France

Data Analyst Apr 2016 - Sep 2016

· Text mining analysis, database structuring and predictive modelling.

# **Publications**

## **Blog Posts**

MEDIUM

- · A. Ouaknine, Review of Deep Learning Algorithms for Image Classification, Medium, January 2018.
- A. Ouaknine, Review of Deep Learning Algorithms for Object Detection, Medium, February 2018.
- A. Ouaknine, Deep Learning Model Compression for Image Analysis: Methods and Architectures, Medium, March 2018.
- A. Ouaknine, Review of Deep Learning Algorithms for Image Semantic Segmentation, Medium, December 2018.

#### **Conferences**

SUBMISSIONS

A. Ouaknine, A. Newson, J. Rebut, F. Tupin and P. Pérez, CARRADA: Camera and Automotive Radar Dataset with Semi-Automatic Range-Angle-Doppler Annotations, Submitted to ICPR 2020.

## Skills

### Languages

FRENCH (NATIVE), ENGLISH (FLUENT)

## **Software Languages**

PYTHON, JAVA, R, JAVASCRIPT, SQL, NOSQL, C++, SCALA, VBA

#### **Frameworks**

Deep Learning: PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras

Software Development: Linux, Docker, Github, CircleCl, Sphinx

## Interests

## **Sports**

ENGLISH BOXING, RUNNING (10 KM, HALF-MARATHON)

## **Travels**

WESTERN AND EASTERN EUROPE, CANADA, USA, GUATEMALA, MAROCCO, CAPE VERDE, CAMBODIA, VIETNAM, INDONESIA,

THAILAND